edarticle.com 2015-12-15

# Privacy And Cookie Policy | Edarticle

Important Note: In order to view full articles, you must consent to receive first and third party cookies from navigating Edarticle.com. If you have not consented, you will see a notification at the top of the page and attempts to access article pages will send you here.

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at admin =at= edarticle =dot= com.

At Edarticle.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information received and collected by Edarticle.com and how it is used.

 **Log Files**

Like many other Web sites, Edarticle.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

 **Cookies and Web Beacons**

Third party cookies may be placed on your computer by third party websites that we have integrated into Edarticle.com such as (but not limited to) Google Analytics, Doubleclick, Media.net and Google Adsense. In addition, we have links to third party websites that may place cookies on your computer and have separate privacy policies. These include, but are not limited to, Lockerz Share, Pinterest, Facebook, Twitter, Blogger and Google Plus. [Google Analytics Cookies](http://helpful.knobs-dials.com/index.php/Utma,_utmb,_utmz_cookies) include _utma, _utmb, and _utmz cookies (and may include other cookies with the pattern _utm*). Google Adsense/Doubleclick may place _gads and __ar_v4 cookies on your computer.

"When a user clicks a Follow button, Google receives information including the URL of the page/profile/community followed, information about the user's Google profile, the user's IP address, and other browser-related information." (from Google)

You can read more about Media.net's ad preferences [here](http://www.media.net/adchoices).

Your continued use of the Edarticle.com website implies that you consent to first and third party cookies being placed on your computer; or you have taken measures to disallow cookies from being placed on your computer through your browser settings or by other means.

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our website. Our advertising partners include:

  * Google Adsense and Doubleclick: [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and [Google Advertising Privacy FAQ](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/)
  * Media.net (Yahoo! Bing Network): [Ad Preferences](http://www.media.net/adchoices) and [Privacy Policy](http://www.media.net/privacy-policy)

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology for the advertisements and links that appear on Edarticle.com and send them directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

Edarticle.com has no access to nor control over the cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Edarticle.com's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites.

 **DoubleClick DART Cookie**

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on Edarticle.com.
  * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit(s) to Edarticle.com and other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie. You can find out more by visiting the [Google Advertising Privacy FAQ](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/).
